Guide to the Mab Segrest Papers, 1889-2014 RL.01164
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Mab Segrest papers
1889-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Segrest, Mab, 1949-
RL.01164
66.6 Linear Feet 119 boxes
Dr. Mab Segrest is a feminist writer, scholar, and activist who received her PhD from Duke University in 1979. She was born in 1949 in Tuskegee, Alabama and attended Huntingdon College from 1967 to 1971. Multiple generations of Dr. Segrest's family have lived in the Tuskegee area and influenced its history and development. Segrest is recognized for speaking and writing about sexism, racism, homophobia, classism, and other forms of oppression. She has founded, served on the boards of, and consulted with a wide range of social justice organizations throughout her life. From its creation in 1969 until it disbanded in 1983, Segrest participated in the southern feminist writing collective Feminary working to produce the journal of the same name. After Feminary disbanded, she worked for six years (1983–1990) with North Carolinians Against Racist and Religious Violence (NCARRV), focusing much of her work on removing the Ku Klux Klan from North Carolina. She earned her livelihood from 1992–2000 as Coordinator of the Urban-Rural Mission (USA), part of the URM network of the World Council of Churches. After working full-time with various political organizations, Segrest returned to academia. From 2002 until 2014, Segrest worked at Connecticut College in New London, Connecticut. In 2004, Segrest was appointed the Fuller-Matthai Professor of Gender & Women's Studies there. She is currently conducting research for a book or series of books about the Central State Hospital in Milledgeville, Georgia. Her major published works include: Living in a House I Do Not Own (Night Heron Press, 1982), My Mama's Dead Squirrel: Lesbian Essays on Southern Culture, (Firebrand Books, 1985), Memoir of a Race Traitor (South End Press, 1994), and Born to Belonging: Writings on Spirit and Justice (Rutgers University Press, 2002).
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Most of the audiovisual components in this accession are not immediately accessible because they require further processing before use. Unless otherwise noted, Technical Services staff need to reformat for use copies of the films.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Mab Segrest papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1991, 1994-1996, 2006, and 2013-2014.
Collection Overview
This collection documents Segrest's personal life, education, and professional life and is comprised of materials related to her family, activism, research, writings, teaching, and travel.
The collection also contains a typescript of Dorothy Allison's Bastard out of Carolina.
There are significant materials relating to Segrest's work with the following organizations: The NC Coalition for Gay and Lesbian Equality, North Carolinians Against Racist and Religious Violence (NCARRV), The Center for Democratic Renewal (CDR), The North Carolina Coalition for Gay and Lesbian Equality (NCCGLE), National Women's Studies Association (NWSA), The World Council of Churches/Urban Rural Mission (WCC/URM), and The National Women's Studies Association/Southern Women's Studies Association (NWSA/SWSA).
Where possible, Segrest's original folder titles have been retained.
Related Materials
Dorothy Allison papers
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Political activists -- Southern States; Gay activists -- Southern States; Civil rights movements -- Southern States; Homosexuality -- Southern States; Gay rights -- North Carolina; Lesbians -- North Carolina; Feminism -- North Carolina; Southern States -- Religious life and customs; Southern States -- Race relations; Allison, Dorothy -- Bastard Out of Carolina
- Correspondence, 1913-2001; 7 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  The series is divided into two chronological subseries: Personal and Professional. In some cases, there is overlap of personal and professional content because of the nature of the relationships Segrest has had with many of her correspondents.
  Personal correspondence includes letters written by members of the Segrest family; most were written to or by Dr. Segrest. Many of the letters to her natal family members address their reactions to her published works. There is also a significant amount of correspondence between Dr. Segrest and her friends and chosen family, including Barbara Culbertson, David Jolly, Ceci Gray, Marquita Seavey, Monica Raymond, Adrienne Rich, Catherine Moriai, Minnie Bruce Pratt, and others.
  Professional correspondence includes letters to and from publishers and editors, letters to and from other writers discussing their work, and correspondence documenting her academic career.
  - Personal, 1913-2000
    - Letters from Daddy, 1913-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Birthday and miscellaneous, 1945-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Music camp letters from grandmother & cousins, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Personal correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Barbara Culbertson, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Ceci Gray, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Marquita Seavey, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Assorted letters, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3, 4)
    - Correspondence with Monica Raymond, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Adrienne Rich correspondence, 1979-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Barbara Deming, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Michelle Cliff, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Shotsy Faust, 1979-1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Catherine Moriai, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1, 2)
    - Correspondence with Diana Rivers, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Minnie Bruce Pratt, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with "Daddy", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Kate White, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Lou Blackdyke Woman, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Dorothy Allison, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Assorted correspondence, 1983-1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Minnie Bruce Pratt, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Adrienne Rich, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Mama, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Mama re: Squirrel, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Letter to my father re Race Traitor and My Mama's Dead Squirrel and his letter to me in response, 1985-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Margaret Randall, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - David Jolly's letter to my parents, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letter from friend re Squirrel, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - My letter to Mama & Daddy re: Barb, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mama's death/funeral, 1987-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters to & from Kirk, my brother-in-law, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Birthday & condolence cards, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Mab's 50th birthday party, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Xmas/home, Christmas 2000 Daddy's stroke (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Aunt Rob & A, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Carl Wittman, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Notes from conversation with my mother after I sent her Squirrel, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Professional, 1978-2001
    - University Drive, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Susan Wood Thompson, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Susan Wood Piece on aesthetics: me, Minnie Bruce, Eliz., 1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Jan Clausen's article, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Elly Bulkin, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Newsletter Collective, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Maureen Brady, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jim Baxter, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Firebrand: Nancy Bereano, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - C. Cade, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Kitchen Table: Barbara Smith, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Lyn Wells, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Pam, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Rev. Wilson Lee, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondences with Nancy Bereano/Squirrel, 1987-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letter to Michelle Cliff, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Michelle's book, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Michelle's letter, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 8, 9)
    - Jim Winders, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Lenny Zeskind, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Ruth Frankenberg, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Bridges, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Minnie Bruce Pratt, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Dorothy Allison, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 16, 17, 18)
    - Duke, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Arlene Stein's paper, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cottages at Hedgebrook, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - UNC Press, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - New Mexico, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Testing the Limits, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Alternative radio, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Andrea Lockett, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Anthologies, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Center for Public Television, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - James Sears, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Jim Sears, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Jim Sears, 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Letters, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Letters from Dorothy Allison, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Letter to Katrina Ramdas, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Jim Sears, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Mab stuff, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Ruth Frankenberg, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Book material, 1997-2002 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Western Kentucky University, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Dangerous Liaisons, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Jim Sears, 1998-2000 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Sears, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Interviewing/Mab, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Rose Norman, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Tamara Powell, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - M. Jacqueline Alexander, Ph.D., 2001 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Early Life and Family, 1889-2009; 13 boxes
  The Early Life and Family Material series is divided into three subseries: Childhood, Education, and Ancestry.
  The Childhood subseries contains materials related to Dr. Segrest's childhood (birth until graduation from high/secondary school).
  The Education subseries includes mostly materials documenting Dr. Segrest's time at Huntingdon College and Duke University.
  The Ancestry subseries contains material documenting Dr. Segrest's family of origin. Material in this series documents Dr. Segrest's family's involvement in Civil War, construction of the Panama Canal, World War II, and other historical events. There is also a small amount of material related to Dr. Segrest's personal life and daughter in this subseries; more can be found in the Correspondence series.
  - Childhood, 1949-1967
    - Birth notes, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Baby membership, Women's Society of Christian Service, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Dedication of marker for Alabama Conf. Female College, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letter from my mother to us - from Miami with picture, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Macon Academy, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - DC Trip, Voice of Democracy, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Piano auditions, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Kamp Kiwanis - counselor, summer '67 & two years in college, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Baby materials, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Childhood, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Better Homes & Gardens Baby Book, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Grammar school, Tuskegee Elementary, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Macon Academy, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Photos, school - Mab, John, Dallas (siblings), undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Pictures: childhood, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Pictures from marker unveiling - me, John, & my mother, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 6th grade autobiography, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Pictures of my brother John as child/infant, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Reminiscences, my autobiography, 7th grade, lots of pictures & report cards, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Education, 1967-1980
    - Huntingdon College, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - College newspaper, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Educational correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Huntingdon College Bachelor of Arts Degree, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Northrop Frye, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Bells and Pomegranates (Huntingdon College Yearbook), 1970 (Box 11)
    - The Ritual Theory of Myth and its Application to the Oresteia, 1971 (Box 11)
    - Trip to Europe with Nora Sue, Becky, Tina, 1972 (Box 11)
    - D.H. Lawrence and Fascism, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Camp Brady: Patterson, NY, 1973 (Box 12)
    - Transcript: A Discussion Between Two Classes In Recent Southern Fiction and Reynolds Price, 1975 (Box 12)
    - The Tree of Life in the Poetry of W.B. Yeats, first full version, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Duke dissertation, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 2, Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Duke University Doctor of Philosophy degree, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Huntingdon College notebook, undated (Box 13)
    - Duke University notebook, undated (Box 13)
    - College correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Freshman English themes, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Dissertation research, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 4-7)
    - Student papers, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Hair is Only Skin Deep! By Lady Godiva, Huntingdon College, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lance and Shield, Macon Academy, Tuskegee, Alabama, Volume III, 1967 (Box 127)
    - Bells and Pomegranates (Huntingdon College Yearbook), 1968 (Box 127)
    - Bells and Pomegranates (Huntingdon College Yearbook), 1969 (Box 127)
    - Bells and Pomegranates (Huntingdon College Yearbook), 1970 (Box 127)
    - Bells and Pomegranates (Huntingdon College Yearbook), 1971 (Box 127)
  - Ancestry, 1889-2009
    - Carrie Laslie description of JE Cobb & bio, war letters, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - WA Campbell, JE Cobb, JH Hunter, FS Price letters, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - DU Barziza, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Grandmother's (Mabelle Massey) writing, 1889-1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Assorted family correspondence, 1904-2000 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mama letters from Mexico UDC Sappho Club, 1909-1954 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Ben Cobb (grandfather) Panama Canal, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Panama Canal materials, Ben Cobb (my grandfather) was engineer on Canal, 1909-1911 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - The Ancient Mariner, The Vision of Sir Launeal, 1909 (Box 16)
    - Sagastaon, 1909 (Box 16)
    - Letter to Ophelia May Segrest from her mother (my father's mother), 1912 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Mother's birth certificate, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Granny's letters on her husband's death from flu in 1920 & from Florida 1917, 1917-1920 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - My mother's poems, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Segrest, Francis C., 1933-1961 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Granny's papers, 1934-1981 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - James E. Cobb obit (great-grandfather) on cover of Race Traitor, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Letters: Mama, 1934-1963 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - The Secret of Victorious Living, 1934 (Box 16)
    - The Radiant Heart: Studies in Paul's Letter to the Philippians, by Costen J. Harrell, 1936 (Box 16)
    - Havana photo, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Frances Hunter Cobb Bachelor of Arts Degree from Huntingdon College, 1938 (Box 16)
    - My Father's citation for Purple Heart WWII, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Daddy's letters from prison camp, 1942-1944 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Letter to John Segrest, Sr. re son wounded, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - The Tuskegee Messenger Fiftieth Anniversary, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Letters between my parents, 1943-1946 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Family letters: mother & sister & father, 1946-1949 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - The United Daughters of the Confederacy Magazine, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Granny, Carrie Cobb, Prelude, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Note from Granny re her husband's death - kept for her children with note, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Bham bombing, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - John Segrest, 1960-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Kennedy Assassination, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - New South, So. Regional Council, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - City of Tuskegee's first integrated City Council, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - The Tuskegee Study: Ala CR Com, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Family pix, 1980-1990 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Her Singing Chorus photo - Durham, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Mab pix, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-2010 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Mab & Barb, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Annie - baby, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Calendar/journals in Mama's desk - mentioned in Memoir, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Mama, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Pictures from Mama's funeral, Macon Co., 1987 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Annie, 1990-1999 (Box 17, Folder 22, 23)
    - Annie Segrest childhood pix, 1990-1999 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Christmas story, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Drawings by Annie, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Annie's writing, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Nat - to & about, 1990-1999 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Mab & Barb commitment celebration pix & trip to Sanibel Island, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - John - correspondence, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Pictures from reception, Dale Segrest's restoration of our house after we bought, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Annie Segrest, 2007-2009 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Annie Segrest - paper for social work on family, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 60th birthday party Atlanta, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Caroline Elizabeth Hunter, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Cobb genealogy, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Cobb records, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Annie Segrest art (1-2 years), undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Daddy - JF Segrest, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Dallas' family - the parting, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - David's letter re: his mom's death, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Fletcher's papers receiving Purple Heart, picture, undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - History of Macon Co AC from Alabama archives & history, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Hurdle Mills: journals, drafts, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Integration, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - JE Cobb portraits, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Mabelle Massey ("Granny") odds & ends, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Mabelle Massey tribute to Sallie Danner at her retirement, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 19, Folder 12, 13, 14)
    - Miscellaneous family photos, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Mother - "Latin P" High School, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Teaching, 1979-2014; 16 boxes
  The Teaching series includes material from Dr. Segrest's experiences teaching at Connecticut College, Duke University, Campbell University, the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, the Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers Association, a minimum security men's prison, and other institutions.
  Dr. Segrest began teaching at Connecticut College in 2002 as a Visiting Assistant Professor and Chair of the Gender and Women's Studies Department; during this time she commuted from Durham, NC to Connecticut regularly.
  The Duke University subseries contains material regarding Dr. Segrest's involvement with the Women's Studies department.
  Dr. Segrest briefly taught at Campbell University and was the faculty advisor for "Lyricist," a language arts publication.
  Dr. Segrest led classes on Queer Southern Literature at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill in the late 1990s.
  The Various Institutions subseries contains assorted material from different institutions of learning that Dr. Segrest has been affiliated with.
  The Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers' Association subseries reflects Dr. Segrest's time teaching English as a Second Language (ESL) in migrant labor camps in the 1980s.
  Dr. Segrest taught a GED course in a minimum security men's prison in the 1980s.
  The Personal Files subseries is mostly composed of calendars, planners, and journals belonging to Dr. Segrest. There are also letters of recommendation and non-specific personal budget information in the subseries.
  - Connecticut College, 2001-2014
    - Fuller-Maathai Professor of Gender and Women's Studies, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Portfolio & evidence of excellence in teaching, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Boston presentation, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Jacqui/readings, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - AmLit response, 2006-2007 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Senior honors seminar, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - GWS steering committee, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Committee work, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - New Orleans, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Reports CFR, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - GWS 104, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Diversity: Kim & Segrest session, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Evals, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - GWS annual report, 2005-2006 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Tenure, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Sabbatical, 2005-2006 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Connecticut College, annual reports, personal & departmental reports, 2003-2014 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Moving Worlds: Celebrating One Hundred Years of Women's Education at Connecticut College, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Learning outcomes for GWS, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Connecticut College Ninety-Sixth Commencement Program, 2014 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - CC papers/letters, 2002 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Gender and Women's Studies assessment plan, 2011 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Introduction to Queer Studies, 2011 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Milledgeville: A Social History of Georgia's State Mental Hospital (draft), 2012 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Transnational Perspectives on Terror Event, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Katrina talk, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Disability, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Engendering the Millennium, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Mab poster, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Angels in Straightjackets, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Dislocating Whiteness, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Sexual Assault & Human Rights, 2005-2012 (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Connecticut College in the news, 2006 (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Connecticut College Magazine, 2006 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Sexual assault on campus, 2006 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - Educating women for a world in crisis, 2007 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Center for the Comparative Study of Race & Ethnicity workshop, 2008 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Nomination statement, King Teaching Award, 2012 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Disability Studies Symposium, 2013 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Trip to India - environmental justice, 2013 (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - Assorted syllabi, undated (Box 128, Folder 10)